cpalms.org 2017-06-12

# CPALMS Privacy Policy

This is the Privacy Policy that applies to (a) the CPALMS website located at _cpalms.org_ and all corresponding web pages, other URLs including www.icpalms.org and thesmartspot.org along with all corresponding web pages, and mobile applications related to these websites are collectively called the ('Website') and (b) any other content, applications, features, functionality, information and services offered by us through the Website (together with the Website, collectively the 'Services'). which are under the control of the Florida Center for Research in Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics at the Florida State University, C4600 University Center, Tallahassee FL 32306. References to 'we', 'our' and 'us' are references to CPALMS.

Please review our [terms and Conditions](http://www.cpalms.org/terms/terms.aspx), which governs your use of the Services. This Privacy Policy will remain in full force and effect, even if your use of or participation in the Services or any particular service, feature, function or promotional activity offered through the Service terminates, expires, ceases, is suspended or deactivated for any reason. If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy, please do not participate in the Services or any features, activities or services offered through the Services. This Privacy Policy applies regardless of the device you use to access the Services and whether you are accessing the Services as a registered user or otherwise.

## Your Information

This Privacy Policy governs only the information collected by us from you, in each instance, on or in connection with your use of the Services, and does not cover any other information collected in any other manner or collected by any other entity, unless specifically stated. We may combine your Information (as defined herein) with other information we collect from other sources, such as information you have provided to third parties, including, but not limited to, the Florida Department of Education, or other sources and have provided sufficient consent, and, if we do so, our use of the resulting combined Information will be subject to this Privacy Policy. The Service may contain links to other websites over which we have no control. We are not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of other websites to which you choose to link from this site. We strongly encourage you to review the privacy policies of those other websites so you can understand how they may collect, use and share your information.

When the term 'Personal Information' is used, we mean any information that we collect on or in connection with the Services that would allow someone to identify you or contact you, such as your full name, address, email address or telephone number. When we use the term 'Additional Information', we mean any information that we collect on or in connection with the Services other than Personal Information, such as your preferences, interests, schedules, reviews, etc. (Personal Information and Additional Information will be collectively referred to as 'Information'). By visiting, accessing or otherwise using the Services, you affirmatively consent to our collection and use of Information in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

We receive a number of different types of information about you, including:

> #### Registration information
> 
> In order to access some features and information, you are required to sign up for an account and create a profile. When you sign up for an account, you are required to provide information such as your name, email address, contact information, content interests, and others. Even when you login using an external authentication service such as the FL Department of Education Single Sign-On system, this information is still being shared with and collected by the Services. 
> 
> #### Information provided while using the Services
> 
> Your information also includes the information you choose to provide during your use of resources, courses, interest selections, communications, etc. In addition, resource submissions/authoring, resource reviews, collaboration with others, sharing with others different parts, provide notes, discussions, feedback, etc. This also includes any information that is provided when contacting support or our team via web, telephone, email, and any professional development training session in a conference, webinar, or workshop setting.
> 
> #### Events, competitions, sweepstakes, applications, promotions, workshops, and surveys
> 
> Participating in, but not limited to, events, competitions, sweepstakes, applications, promotions, survyes, and workshops might include a seperate registration process that may require the submission of Information. We will use the Information for the purpose of using the Services and related events and promotions. 
> 
> #### Automated data
> 
> The Services include features that automatically gather information about your visits, your use of the Services, and other information. This includes but not limited to demographic data, browsing patterns, searching patterns, IP address, computer capabilities and settings (e.g., resolution, operating system and version, browser and version, etc.), and geographical location. Collecting this information is mainly used to customize the user's experience on the website and to inform development of new features. We might use third-party software applications to track this data. We may associate the information obtained, and other identifiers and data, with your Personal Information so we can better customize your experience using the Services and provide tailored recommendations, promotions and other content related to your specific interests, activities or profile. By visiting and using the Services, whether as a registered user or otherwise, you acknowledge, understand and hereby agree that you are giving us your consent to track your activities and your use of the Service as described in this Privacy Policy. 
> 
> You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set. (Each browser is different, so check the 'Help' menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences.) Please note that if you do disable cookies, certain services on this Website may not be available. 
> 
> #### Information others share about you
> 
> When others use the Services they may store and some information about you and others that they have, such as when they upload and manage their class timeline, class resources, lesson plan and/or resources, district schedules, invitation, etc. We may receive information about you from the Florida Department of Education, your organization, partners, or any other user. 

## Data collection from children

We do not knowingly collect personal information from U.S. children under 13 without appropriate parental notice and consent.

## Use of Information

Personal Information, including, without limitation, your contact and other details you supply as part of the registration process will be used by us to authenticate your identity, deal with your inquiries and requests and to provide you with any services or products you request in connection with the Services (including to process your submissions and administer your account) and contacting you regarding the administration of any features of the Services or features you have registered to use. 

> #### How we use your personal information
> 
> We may also use Your (Personal) Information for other purposes, including, without limitation:
> 
>   * To personalize aspects of the Services;
>   * To carry out market research surveys;
>   * To contact you about opportunities that we believe may be relevant to you and to provide you with updates about developments on the sites and information about new resources, lesson plans, changes in standards, services we offer, etc.; and
>   * For other purposes disclosed at the time you provide us with the Personal Information or which are reasonably necessary to provide the services or other related products requested.
> 

> 
> #### How we use additional information
> 
> We may use Additional Information for many purposes, including, without limitation the following:
> 
>   * Accumulating, reporting and disclosing aggregate (so that no individuals are identified) information in connection with the Services and user activity;
>   * For research, marketing, strategic development purposes (i.e., to identify usage trends across different content areas, such as lesson plan adoption by subject areas); and
>   * Saving some information incrementally in order to establish timeline trends, for the uses described in 'How we use your personal information' above; 
> 

> 
> It is your responsibility to ensure that any information submitted, as part of the registration process to your user account, is accurate and up to date.
> 
> #### Public records
> 
> Some of the information may be saved for a designated period of time to comply with Florida's archiving policies, but we will not disclose the information to other third parties or government agencies, unless required to do so by state or federal law or in support of building the Services.
> 
> _Under Florida law, e-mail addresses are public records. If you do not want your e-mail address released in response to a public-records request, do not send electronic mail, provide your e-mail address on an of the forms when using our Services, register for an account, or contact our support via e-mail._

## Additional disclosures

There may be instances when we may access or disclose Information without providing you a choice in the following circumstances: (a) to protect or defend our legal rights or property, our affiliated organizations or their employees, agents and contractors (including enforcement of our agreements); (b) to protect the safety and security of our Service and users; (c) protect against fraud or for risk-management purposes; (d) if we believe your actions violate the [terms and Conditions](http://www.cpalms.org/terms/terms.aspx), this Privacy Policy, any Rules and/or Additional terms; or (e) to comply with law or legal process.

We may need to or be required to update this Privacy Policy from time to time. Your continued use of the Services after we post a revised Privacy Policy signifies your acceptance of the revised Privacy Policy. It is therefore important that you review this Privacy Policy regularly to ensure that you are aware of any changes. If we materially change our practices regarding collection, use or disclosure of your personal information, your personal information will continue to be governed by the Privacy Policy under which it was collected unless you have been provided notice of, and have not objected to, the change. Where necessary and appropriate we may contact you through the email address that you have provided, to advise you of a change. All changes will be accessible from the Services through the Privacy Policy.

## Contact us 

For questions or reporting violations, please contact us at:

Florida Center for Research in Science, Technology, Engineering and Mathematics  
Learning Systems Institute, Florida State University  
4600 University Center C  
Tallahassee, FL 32306-2540

For phone or email contact, please contact us using the information on the following webpage: <http://www.cpalms.org/support/support_homepage.aspx>
